Finding Aid for the Elizabeth Vann Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- EUGENE ELLIS VANN: INCOMING CORHESPONDENCE FROM FELIX (Box 34)
  - 1952: Aug.14,17; Dec.31. (Box 34)
  - 1955: June 5. F 3. (Box 34)
- EUGENE ELLIS VANN: INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE FROM FRIEND (Box 34)
  - Aorold. 1951: Feb.14. 1957: Dec.14. (Box 34)
  - David. 1914: Aug.4. (Box 34)
  - Eddie. 1934: Mar.22. F 4. (Box 34)
  - Baillie, Arthur C. n.d. Newspaper clipping. (Folder B, Box 34)
    1921: Dec.13. 1922: May 9; July 25.
    1929: Jan.18,21(2). 1934: Mar.12(2),17,18,23(2).
    1938: June 10; July 20. F 5.
  - Becklin, Harold M. (10) photographs of children, n.d. (Box 34)
    1961: June 22.
    Daughter’s wedding invitation. F 6.
  - Beckraan, R. Livingston. (Box 34)
    (l)n.d. F 7.
  - Bodet, Robert G. Speech outline, n.d. (Box 34)
    1948: Apr.26.
    1949: Jan.18; Feb.8,15.
    1961: Mar.3.
    1965: July 19.
    Article with picture, 1949. F 8
  - Bruce, J.L. (Box 34)
    1914: June 25
    Aug.6,21,24
    Sept.9,21.
    Oct.11
    (lp.)n.d.
    Nov.7
    Dec.18.
    1915: Apr.28
    Sept.17
    Oct.3,17
    1917: Feb.4. F 9.
  - Charlton, Charles M., 1908: Apr.4. F 10. (Box 34)
  - Cuadra, Maria Christina., 1963: Nov. 17. F 10. (Box 34)
  - Fletcher, Walter. Newspaper picture, 1947. (Folder F)
    Program for reception in his honor, 1971.
    1948: May 15.
    1950: Jan.28.
    1951: Aug.31.
    1962: Apr.16(to A.J. Morris), 24
    Aug.10. F 11.
  - Glasgow, Benjamin B. & Signa. (Box 34, Folder G)
    1910: Oct.19(to Elizabeth Vann), 26; Nov.10.
    1927: Feb.19.
    1934: Mar.17; Apr.1(to Elizabeth Vann), 17.
    1958: Apr.12. F 12.
  - Hill, Roscoe R. (Box 34, Folder H)
    1952: Aug.19; Sept.17. F 15.
  - Kern, Alfred Allen. (Box 34, Folder K)
    1910: July ?; Oct.12. F 14.
    1907: Apr.l; Sept.19. (4) n.d.
  - Lambeth, Walter R. (l)n.d. (Box 34, Folder L)
    1907: Mar.1,9; June 15(to C.H. Walker).
    1909: Feb.16,26; Mar.18; May 13; Sept.13; Nov.15; Dec.11.
    1910: Apr.25; July 25(to Mrs. Collins Denny); Sept.1.
    1911: Mar.3(to Elizabeth Vann).
    1913: Aug.12(to Elizabeth Vann); Oct.3.
    1914: July 28; Aug.14; Sept.5(to Elizabeth Vann). F 1
  - Lopez, Francisco E.(Frank) (Box 34, Folder L)
    Newspaper clipping, 1949.
    Photographs of’ wife and children, 1949 & 1962(5) and office staff (2).
    A Spanish magazine.
    1949: May 11; July 25.
    1950: Feb.10; Mar.8; May 3.
    1951: Dec.15.
    1952: Mar.27.
    1954: Nov.24.
    1955: Dec.15
    1956: Oct.31.
    1959: Sept.8.
    1960: Apr.8.
    1961: Feb.13; Oct.16.
    1973: Dec.?(to Elizabeth Vann).
    1974: May 15(to Elizabeth): Dec.22(to Elizabeth).
    1975: July 10(to Elizabeth). F 16.
  - McMurry, W.F., 1910: Nov.30. F 17. (Box 34, Folder M)
  - Morel, Roger. (l)n.d., 1956: Aug.22. F 17. (Box 34)
  - Murray, Alex., 1932: June 14. F 17. (Box 34)
  - Nicoll, W. Robertson., 1909: Aug.30. F 17. (Box 34, Folder N)
  - Phipps, Delmar., 1963: Dec.13. F 18. (Box 34, Folder P)
  - Pisani, B.J. (l)n.d., 1961: Jan.19. F 18. (Box 34)
  - Pomar, Iisi., 1964: Feb.13. F 18. (Box 34)
  - Pontius, Miller H. Stock market charts. (Box 34)
    1922: Dec.7(to Elizabeth Vann).
    1954: Dec.16.
    1959: Feb.26. F 19.
  - Punciman, Gladys., 1960: Apr.22. F 19. (Box 34)
  - Rowbotham, J., 1956: Jan. 17; Apr. 11. F 19. (Box 34, Folder R)
  - San Miguel, Marcelino., 1954: Jan.26. F 20. (Box 34, Folder S)
  - Scott, Frank L. (Box 34)
    1953: Dec.16.
    1954: Obituary. F 20.
  - Scott, Frank L. (son). (l)n.d. (Box 34)
    1954: Dec.15.
    1959: Apr.18. F 20.
  - Tucker, H.C. (Box 34, Folder T)
    1910: Apr.2,19,30; May 16,30; June July 18; Aug.1,18; Sept.16.
    1912: Mar.29; Oct.18; Dec.5,12.
    1913: Mar.24; Apr.1,11.
    1914: Dec.15.
    1915: Apr.19.
    1951: Jan.4.
    1955: Dec.17. F 21.
  - Turner, Anna Maria(Mrs. John). (l)n.d. F 21. (Box 34)
  - Whaling, Morlan M., Jr. (2)n.d. (Box 34, Folder W)
    1907: ?; July 26(to Elizabeth Vann); Aug.27(to Elizabeth); Sept.26; Dec.10,26.
    1908: Jan.26; Feb.22; Mar.23,30; Apr.27; June ?; Dec.?.
    1909: Jan.27,29; Apr.30; June 24; July 27; Nov.26.
    1910: ?(2); June 27.
    1913: ?(1).
    1914: Oct.4. F 22.
  - Wailes, W.L.C., 1907: Jan.14. F 25. (Box 34)
  - Wilcox, Robert. (Box 34)
    1945: Feb.17.
    1960: Aug.14 - from ?
    Article about daughter, Anna Mae Wilcox Hottel. F2” Wilson, Dudley A. 1951: Apr.18. F 25.
  - Valdez - Valmana, Luis., 1959: Dec.28. F 24. (Box 34, Folder V)
  - Zavale, Joaquin Cuadra. 1963: Nov.7. F 24. (Box 34, Folder Z)
    Hamlet. William Shakespeare.
    Novo Testamento. Joao Ferreira d’Almeida.
    Western Breezes or Ballads of a Gringo. Randolph Henry Atkin.
- EUGENE ELLIS VANN: COLLEGES, JOBS, BRAZIL, POLITICAL, ACTIVITIES, HEALTH (Box 35)
  - Autobiographical Notes, “History of the Vann Family” by M.K. Vann, 1894. Repro. 1974. “The Vann Family in Ale (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Birmingham - Southern College: Correspondence Incoming Correspondence to Eugene from: (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Englebert, H. Ben 1955: Nov.23. 1958: ?(2). 1963: ?.
    Hamilton, Walter F. 1956: Oct. ?.
    Hughes, Margaret 1959: May 25.
    Locklear, O.B. 1958: ?.
    McMahon, Virginia D. 1955: May 20.
    Norton, Edward Lee n.d. 1965: June 1.
    Phillips, Howard M. 1964: May 7; June 25.
    Sadler, Robert H. 1961: June 1,20,30. 1962: May 7
    Snavely, Guy E. 1957: Jan.23; Mar.7.
    Stanford, Henry King 1960: Apr.18.
    Thomas, Howard J. n. d.
    Vann, David J. 1960: Apr. 5.
    Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene:
    1955: Nov.17(to Edward Lee Norton)
    1957: Jan.19(to Dr. Guy S. Snavely.Pres.) Jan.28(to Dr. Guy E. Snavely) 1960: Apr.6(to H. Ben Englebert)
    Apr.7(to Dr. Henry King Stanford)
  - Birmingham - Southern College: Newspaper Clippings, Certificate(50 year), The Decision for Excellence., 1957-61. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - “The Captivity,”the essay for which Eugene won The Owen Prize Medal at Vanderbilt in 1907., Newspaper Clipping: The Nashville American. 1904: Dec.17(about Eugene in debate) (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Brazil: Newspaper Clippings, Report of the Mission, Expenses. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Clippings: Go Forward(about Eugene)n.d.
    The Tennessean. 1973: Aug.9(death of R.B. Eleazer)
    World Outlook. 1935: Aug.(about H.C. Tucker) Other clippings, n.d.
  - Brazil: Photographs (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Photograph of Eugene talien in Juiz de FPra.
    Photograph of the American Colony in Rio when William Jennings Bryan visited there. Vanderbilt University: Photographs
  - Brazil: Job at Granbery College - Incoming Correspondence to Eugene, 1913-1915 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Columbia University, Master of Arts Degree, 19-14-15 Commencement Program etc. 1915 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Newspaper Clipping, New York Times. 1915: Apr.18 Incoming Correspondence from:
    Incoming Correspondence to Campbell, IV.B. Collins, James H. Crawford, C.H. Denny, Rev. Collins IIoss, E.E.
    Egbert, James C. 1915: Jan.14
    Fackenthal, Frank B. 1915: Apr.5
    Prince, John D. 1915: May 15
  - Incoming Correspondence to Eugene, 1915 - 1921 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Leland Stanford University., Announcement of Courses, 1915-1916 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Incoming Correspondence to Engene: (Box 35)
      - Branner, J.C., May 16; July 24; Sept.5,23; Dec.4,18 1917: Jan.8; Feb.20; Mar.9; May 29; Sept.20 1918: May 9; July 29 1919: Feb.5,25; Sept.2 1920: May 22; June 26 1915: May 1 (Box 35)
      - Clark, G.A., 1915: May 1 (Box 35)
    - Mez, John & Lockmen, L.P., 1915: Sept.11 (Box 35)
    - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene:, 1919: Oct.23(to J.C. Branner) 1920: July 21(to Dr. Horace Williams) July 22(to J.C. Branner) (Box 35)
  - Leland Stanford University - Correspondence Incoming Correspondence to Eugene: (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Adam E.D., 1916: Aug.28 1917: Sept.20 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Espinoso, Aurelio M., 1916: Doc.11 (Box 35)
    - Martin, Percy A., 1915: Jan.3; Feb.9; Mar.30; Apr.7,8,13,14; May 10. 10(to G.F. Bovard), 11(from G.F. Bovard to Eugene); July 1; Oct.9 1916: July 11; Oct.28; Nov.3 1917: Apr.16; Sept.5; Dec.13 1918: Jan.9 1919: Apr.4; Aug.27 1920: June 18 1922: Jan.2; May 10 1923: Aug.9,24; Sept.19 1924: Mar.30 1926: Apr.4; Dec.20 1927: Nov.14; Dec.3 1930: Oct.6; Nov.15 1932: July 25; Aug.8 (Box 35)
  - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene: (Box 34)
    - 1917: Oct.18(to Percy A. Martin) (Box 34)
    - 1919: Aug.31(to Percy A. Martin) (Box 34)
    - 1926: Apr.24(Percy A. Martin), 26(Col. Perrin C. Cothran) (Box 34)
    - 1927: Nov.2(Percy A. Martin); Dec.13(Percy A. Mart: Dec.14(Frank B. Fackenthal), 14(Prof. Louis A. Imbert), 16(Percy A. Martin) (Box 35)
    - 1930: Oct.24(Percy A. Martin) (Box 35)
    - 1932: Aug.1(Percy A. Martin) (Box 35)
  - Leland Stanford University - Percy A. Martin (Box 35, Folder 12)
    Newspaper Clipping - The San Francisco News. 1936:
    Apr.14,15 Articles - “Brazil and the War” 1920
    “Influences of the United States on the Opening of the Amazon to the World’s Commerce” 1918
  - Columbia University - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Incoming Correspondence to Eugene from: (Box 35)
      - Klingberg, Frank J., 1916: June 6(to William R. Shepherd); July 3 (Box 35)
      - Shepherd, William R., 1915: Nov.20; Dec.15 1916: Mar.3; May 19; June 17; Oct.31; Dec.l 1917: Mar.14; June 5 1919: Oct.10 1920: Feb.16 (Box 35)
    - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene:, 1916: Feb.23(to William R. Shepherd) 1919: Dec.31(to William ft. Shepherd) (Box 35)
  - Vita for War Mission to Brazil, 1917 Passport (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Incoming Correspondence to Eugene from: (Box 35)
      Barrett, John 1917: July 9, 9(to Dr.W.II. Faunce)
      Faunce, W.H.C. 1917: July 5
      Long, Breckenridge 1917: July 12
      Rowe, L.S. 1917: July 5,9
      Slosson, Edwin E. 1917: July 8
      Underwood, E. Marvin 1917: July 9,13
    - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene:, 1917: July 5( to Hon. Josephus Daniels), July 9(to Hon. Breckenridge Long); Denny, Rev. Collins to The President of the United States n.d. (Box 35)
  - Brown University - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene: (Box 35, Folder 15)
    n.d.(Dear Sir)(2)
    n.d.(W.H.P. Faunce, Pres.) telegram
    1916: Mar.27
    1917: Oct.18(Dr. Harry Lyman Koopman)
    1921: May 27(F.W. Latson)
    1933: Oct.6(3.A. Burlingame), 13(Ruy Lowndes)
    1934: Feb.§(Ruy Lowndes), 10(F.W. Latson); May 9(S.A. Burlingame)
  - Brown University - Incoming Correspondencefrom: (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Burlingame, E.A., 1933: Oct.3,7; 1934: May 10 (Box 35)
    - Drury, F.K.W., 1921: Mar.9 (Box 35)
    - Faunce, W.H.P., 1916: Mar.20; Apr.6,18 May 23,2; June 17; Aug. 22 ? 1917: June 11,’11(To Whom it may Concern) (Box 35)
    - Finch, Arthur, B., 1917: Mar. 10 (Box 35)
    - Johnson, Albert B., 1916: June 6 (Box 35)
    - Koopman, H.L., 1917: Oct.19. 1921: Mar.9 (Box 35)
    - Lowndes, Ruy, 1934: Jan. 19; Mar.6 (Box 35)
    - Randall, Otis E., 1917: June 4 (Box 35)
  - Brown University - Course Descriptions, 1916-1917, Song Sheet, Newspaper Clipping (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Portuguese and Spanish Books and Courses, Receipts, Questionaires (Box 35, Folder 18)
    Receipts for books ordered, 1921
    1916: June 6(to William R. Shepherd); July 3
    Questionaires(sent to colleges to find out which ones were teaching Portuguese)
    Sent to: Boston
    Colurabia(2)
    Cornell
    George Washington University
    Harvard
    Kansas
    Leland Stanford
    Notre Dame
    Pan American Union
    Simmons
    University of Illinois
    University of Oregon
    University of Pennsylvania
    University of Virginia
    University of Wisconsin
    Yale
    Incoming Correspondence from Publishers:
    Benjamin H. Sanborn & Co. 1916: Dec.6
    Ginn & Co. 1917: June 14;. July 2,9,14; Nov. 6 1918: Dec.10 1920: Feb.11; June 10
    The Macmillan Co. 1916: Jan.27; Feb.11
    South American Publishing Co. 1916: Sept.25
    1919: Feb.17(Ginn & Co.)
    1920: July 3KGinn & Co.)
  - National City Bank of New York - Outgoing Correspondence from Eugene: (Box 35, Folder 19)
    1917: Dec.31(E.A. Groff)
    1918: Jan.15(S.A. Groff); Apr.12(3.A. Groff)
    1919: Aug.KJ.L. Cross)
    1920: Jan.27(Frederick Todd); Aug.26(H.E. Freund)
    1923: May 3(J.J. Filey), 31(Corn Exchange Bank,NY), May 31 (C.J. Ca.mpbell)
  - National City Bank of New York - Incoming Correspondence to Eugene (by date): (Box 35, Folder 20)
    1917: Aug.25(from John H. ?, Vice-Pres.)
    1918: Feb.26(from E.A. Groff); Hay ?(G. Amsincl & Co.)
    1919: Jan.20(F.A. ?, Pres.)
    Mar.3(F.N. Mearten?, Vice-Pres.)
    May 21(C.O. Sheehan, Ass't. Cashier)
    June 13( ?); Sept.22(H.S. Titus, Vice-Pres.); Dcc.19(Frederick Todd)
    1920: May 12(A.W. Little); July 31(Sanford H.E. Freund); Nov.24(Everett Drown)
    May 12(A.W. Little); July 31(Sanford H.E. Freund); Nov.2A(Everett Brown)
    Oct.10(SRO ?); Nov.4(W.B. Williams)
    Feb.19(J.L. Fagan ?); May 15(J.L. Fagan)
    May 4(L.O. ?, Ass’t. Cashier)see folder 35-19.
    May 29(with copy of Cashier’s Check), May 31
    1920: Aug.21(Compania Constructora Impanema)
    Copy of tax statement - 1920: Oct.5
  - Letters of Recommendation and Introduction for Eugene from: (Box 35, Folder 21)
    (1)n.d. J. L. Bruce to ____________.
    1911: Apr.15 Dean Wilbur F. Tillett, Biblical
    1915: Mar.18 David Lambeth to Whom It Hay Concern.
    1917: Sept.3 ?, Assistant Professor of Philosophy, College of the City of New York, To Whom It May Concern.
    1921: Oct.6 (Embassy of the United States)
    Oct.18 C.H. Crawford, Baldwin Locomotive Works, to R.K. Johnson.
    1922: Feb.16 The Home Insurance Co., A.C. Baillie)
    Feb.16 The Franklin Fire Insurance Co., Wilfred Kurth)
    Feb.17 International Banking Corp.(2)
    Nov.16 Franklin Fire Insurance Co., Kurth.
    Nov.16 The Home Insurance Co., Kurth.
  - Health: Eugenics - Forms to fill out and publications, 1915 - 1933 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Health: Life Extension Institute, 1922-1924 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    “Survey of physical condition, family and personal history and activities of Mr. Eugene E. Vann,” (2) 1922: Sept.19
    A list of Eugene Vann’s clothing sizes, 1935. Folder 2if: Political Interests, 1937 - 1967
  - Political Interests, 1937 - 1967 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    Certificate: War Bonds, 1943
    Guest ticket to Republican National Convention, 1948
    Leonia Board of Education Information Sheet, n.d.
    Leonia Democratic Club to Citizens of Leonia, 1935: Oct.18
    Newspaper clipping about Leonia Democratic Club, Congressional Record, U.S. Senate
    Incoming Correspondence to Eugene from:
    Bower-man, Walter B. 1964: Aug.4
    Book-of-the-Month Club 1952: May 21
    Ferber, Fred 1961: Sept.29
    Kennedy, Robert & Ethel 1964: Jan.10
    Letts, Harold 1964: Jan,5
    Sherhezz(?)(Sect.,HEW) 1963: May 3
    Tannenbaum, Frank 1960: Sept.27
    Time ,., 1950: Nov.l
    The Tuscalossa News 1957: Feb.21
    1956: Mar.7(to Senator Albin W. Barkley)
    1963: Feb.14(President John F. Kennedy)
    1964: Aug.1(memo to Walter Bowerman)
  - Leonia (NJ) Civic Conference, Borough Council (Box 35, Folder 25)
    Pamphlets
    Newspaper clippings, 1935-1964
    Certificates of Election, 1940, 1943
    Candidate Information, 1937(2)
    “Leonia Civic Conference in Retrospect” by Eugene E. Vann, 1964: Nov.18
    Allan, Alexander 1943: Nov.17
    Voorhis, John W. 1947: Jan.9
    Wilson, Dudley 1965: Dec.29
    1964: Nov.19(to Dudley Wilson)
  - Leonia Community Association, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    Program booklets, 1936
    Constitution
    Receipt
    List of members
    Letter from Fred Clarke, President. 1935: Nov.2
- EUGENE ELLIS VANN: ARTICLES AND SPEECHES - THE HOME INSURANCE COMPANY, RETIREMENT, RACE RELATIONS,CORRESPONDENCE (Box 36)
  - “The Old Commuter,” articles in Leonia Life. 1948-1950 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Index and typewritten copies of “The Old Commuter” articles. Some newspaper clippings (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, Newspaper Clippings (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - “The Leonia Civic Conference in Retrospect” (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Speech to Leonia Forum, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - “Notes on My Extended Trip Through Europe,” given to Leonia Lions Club, 1954: Oct.6 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Day Speeches given by Eugene, Newspaper clipping, 1949: May 26 Speeches - 1948 and 1949 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - The Whetstone Club (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Notes for speeches
    Speeches 1961(2) and 1963
    Letter from Charles T. Douds, 1961: Jan.3
  - No folder. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - The Home Insurance Co. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Agreement of Merger, 1948
    Clippings from company newsletters: 1946, 1948, 1949, 1951, 1959, 1960.
    Notice of stockholders meeting, 1948 and 1960.
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Publications (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Annual Dinner Programs and Report (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Newspaper clippings (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Clippings about: Fletcher, Walter, Home Insurance Co. Kurth, Wilfred Loughin, Charles A. Peterson, Leonard Rushin, Robert Vann, Eugene Wilcox, Robert Agreement of Merger, 1948
    - Seguros Franzas(2 copies) (Box 35)
    - Letters from Richard Deimel Vann to Eugene, 1949: Feb.12,26 (Box 35)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Photographs (Box 36, Folder 11)
    Photographs of: Harold Smith
    25th Annual Dinner in honor of Harold V. Smith, 1935: Feh.l
    Eugene with two unidentified men (233#7 on back)
    Mr. Smith(?) and unidentified man (233 #27 on back)
    Eugene and four unidentified men(233 #10 on back)
    Four unidentified men (233 #35 on hack)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Expense Accounts, 1939-1948 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Correspondence, 1923-1961 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    J.A.M.(?) 1938: Jan.1
    Fosdick, Keeland s. 1952: Jan.28
    Home Insurance Co. 1923: Apr.6
    Johnson, Ralph 1961: Mar.17
    Kennedy, W.A. 1951: Apr.19
    Kurth, Wilfred 1928: Mar.?
    Meliorter, Sam 1930: Oct.23
    Rushin, Robert 1952: Jan.15
    Stroub, George E. 1959: Oct.27
    Sharp, Frederick D. 1938: Apr.16
    Whitcomb, Lee 1941: June 13 1947: May 3 1951: May 15
    1945: Jan.17(to Harold V. Smith)
    1947: Mar.25(to Wilfred Kurth)
    May 29(to Lee Whitcomb)
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Retirement, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    A clipping
    Poems: “An Executive Retires”
    “Retirement”
    A. Harvey & Co. Ltd 1948: June 30
    Agendas Unidas, S.A. May 31; June 3
    Aruba Trading Co. June 2
    Bournigal, J.R. July 1
    Braegger, Victor June 1
    Curacao Trading Co. May 31
    Fletcher, W. Robert May 31
    Fletcher, Walter May 28
    Ganteaume. L.E. June 2
    Herrera, Manuel M. May 29
    Johnson, Sprague(J.B.S.) Kean, Osmond, June 10
    Leon, D.C. June 2
    Lopez, Frank ?
    Malone, Ralph(3) May 27; June 14,18
    Meyer, Henry J. June 7
    Morris E. Curiel & Sons, Inc.(2)June 3,7
    Munch, William June 4
    Noa, Lorenzo J. June 2
    Naude, F. Georges June 1
    Pennington, William June 16
    Phipps, Jules May 31
    Postelle, Guy June 10
    Reinhardt, Henry B. July 31
    Robert L. Merwin & Co., Inc. May 31
    Scott, Frank(2) June 21. 1949: Nov.16
    Stroub, George E. May 25
    Urtecho, Ernesto Martinez June 7
    Wilcox, Robert June 8
    1948: May 24-25 - Form letters announcing retirement sent to:
    A.Harvey & Co., Ltd. Agendas Unidas, S.A. Aruba Trading Co.
    Bournigal, J.R. Braegger, Victor Brown, Philip S.
    Caron, Louis Casellas, Miguel Curacao Trading Co.
    Fletcher, Walter Ganteaume, L.E. Herrera, Manuel M.,11. Johnson, J.B.S. Kean, Osmond
    Leon, David C. Lopez, Frank E.
    Malone, R.G.
    Morris E. Curiel & Sons, Inc. Munch, William
    Naude, F. Georges Noa, Lorenzo J.
    Pennington, William Phipps, Jules
    Robert L. Merwin & Co., Inc. Rosenberg, Federico
    San Miguel, Marcelino Scott, Frank
    Urtecho, Ernesto Martinez 1948: May 27 to Beyer. ? Vice-Pres.,
  - The Home Insurance Co.: Greeting Cards, (13) Cards Cork carving from Shanghai, sent by Ruby Lewis Larson, 1948: May 28 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Human Progress, Newspaper clippings Labor Relations Re-porter. 1950: May 15 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Race Relations, Newspaper articles about Dr. Mary McLeod Bethune; 1952 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    “The South Carolina Struggle for Equality”
    Resolution by Englewood Citizens’
    Union Petition form
    List of subversive organizations compiled by the Attorney General of the United States
    “New Jersey’s Stake in the Federal Civil Rights Bill” by George S. Pfaus
    American Council on Human Relations.1958: Oct.24
    Johnson, Charles S.(Fisk Univ.) 1956: Oct.11
    National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 1952: Apr.30
    National Committee for Rural Schools, Inc. n.d.
    1952: May 7 (to William J. Fitzpatrick, Chm. Board of Education, Englewood, NJ)
  - The South (Box 36, Folder 18)
    Newspaper clippings about the South
    Pamphlets about Virginia
    “Colonial Order of the Crown”
    The Lost Cause: A Confederate War Record. Vol.4,No.12, July, 1901
    “Importance of Personality in History” Speech on the 14th Amendment
    “A Twice-Born Book” by J.W. Duffey (from the files of Bishop Collins Denny)
  - Poems, Art (Box 36, Folder 3)
- EUGENE ELLIS VANN - AUTOGRAPHS, SURGERY, RETIREMENT ACTIVITIES, OBITUARIES, MEMORIAL SERVICE, CORRESPONDENCE (Box 36)
  - Art from Eugene’s Study Poems (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Poems (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Stories and Quotations (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Autographs (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Alben Barkley, United States Senator from Kentucky Theodore Roosevelt, President of the United States
  - Installation of Dwight D. Eisenhower as President of Columbia University, 1948 - A Program (Box 37, Folder 5)
    “Mr. President Eisenhower” by Quentin Reynolds in Life
  - American Geographical Society, Certificate when elected a Fellow 1949: Jan.18 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Receipts from Trip to Cuba, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Surgery, Englewood Hospital, 1949: Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 8)
    (14)Greeting cards
    Telegrams from Gual, Francisco Garcia Smith, Harold V.
    Incoming Correspondence to’ Eugene from:
    Henry. ? n.d.
    Henry & Margarita 1950: Sept.30 _B.__n.d.
    John ?__1950: Jan.15
    Bert_?__1950: Jan. 12
    Beyer, W. 1950: Jan.31
    Braegger, Victor 1950: Jan.24
    Gautreau, Gaston 1950: Mar.24
    Hammond, Frances H. 1949: Dec.4
    Hevia, Gerardo 1950: Apr.28
    Hill, Roscoe R. 1949: Dec.10. 1950: Jan.19
    Kennedy, W.A. 1949: Dec.10. 1950: Jan.19
    Lopez, Frank(Francisco E.)1949: Dec.2,16
    Malone, Ralph 1949: Dec.2. 1950: Jan.9
    Marson, Mollie 1949: Dec.22(to Elizabeth)
    Meliorter, Sam 1950: Jan.10
    O'Leary, Cora B. 1949: Nov.29
    Pepe ?__1950: Mar. 9
    Pomar, Iisi 1949: Dec.29
    Quaid, William 1949: Nov.27. 1950: Feb. 1
    Reinhardt, H.B. 1949: Dec.12. 1950: Jan.9,16
    Rodman, Mae 1949: Dec.19
    Rowan, Phil 1949: Nov.28
    San Miguel, Marcelino 1950: Jan.9
    Scott, Frank 1949: Dec.15
    Stroub, George 1949: Nov.23
    Vann, F. Young 1949: Dec.12
    Vann, Leonard L. 1949: Dec.7
    Vann, Monroe 1950: Jan.24
    Whitcomb, Lee 1949: Dec.3
    White, Roscoe 1949: Dec.14
    Cancelled checks and hospital bills
  - Englewood Hospital Association: Correspondence, 1949-64 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Social Security, 1948-50 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Incoming correspondence to Elizabeth from the Federal Security Agency., 1950: Apr.10; July 11(2) (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - From W. Beyer to Harold v. Smith., 1948: Dec.? (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Outgoing correspondence from Eugene
      1948: Dec.4(to Harold v. Smith),
      Dec.13(to Federal Security Agency. Social Security Board),
      Dec.13(to u.s. Treasury Dept).
      1949: Jan.4(to u.s. Treasurery Dept.)
      1950: Jan.27(to Henry B. Reinhardt)
      Mar.16(to Federal Security Agency)
      Apr.18(to Social Security Board)
  - Retirement Activities (Box 37, Folder 11)